- Lukas?
- What?
What if we just talk to him?
He let the baby off.
He might let the kids off too.
What do you wanna do?
Just go to him and ask him?
We have to try something.
Leave it alone. Why provoke him?
What do you mean?
They're children. They shouldn't be here.
- What? And we should?
- Come on. That's not what he's saying.
They think they are better than us.
I'm just saying they're kids.
- And I'm saying we should just ask.
- Hey.
I think we're past asking.
She's got something.
In her bag. I can't…
can't quite see it.
Hello, Sam.
The convoy is about half an hour
from Bergmannstrasse.
Hey!
- Go, just keep going.
- Sam?
Fuck. Shit.
I've seen one of those under the train.
- Attached to the bombs.
- Sam, is everything okay?
If that is the detonator,
we need to get it.
No, no, no, no.
Why would we have to make things worse?
I haven't seen a gun, a knife. Anything.
He must have a gun.
- Couldn't even do this without one.
- Have you seen it?
Have you?
No, because he's not armed.
And he's on his own.
And there are plenty of us back here.
If we all went together as one,
if we had a weapon, we'd have a chance.
He said there were bombs, okay?
What if he pulls the trigger?
If there are bombs,
then we need to get to him
- before that happens.
- Come this way please.
Everything's gonna be okay.
You can turn the lights off
from in here, right?
- Sam, are you there?
- Yes.
- Like, the whole train?
- Yeah.
Sam? Come in.
I will speak to you when I'm ready.
Okay, we just wanted to confirm
that everything is on track
for the handover.
Did you have any reason
to believe that it wouldn't be?
- No.
- No? Okay, good.
So, we have an agreement. Don't bother us
until we get to Bergmannstrasse, okay?
- I'm going to go up there.
- And me.
Maybe I could go talk to him?
- Colin, think about the kids.
- I am. You stay with them.
How about we just wait a bit longer?
We have waited enough.
Okay. One minute.
What?
One minute from now,
flip the switch.
Otto, one minute.
Think about it.
He let that baby off the train.
If we all just stay back here,
I'm pretty sure
he'll let the rest of us off too.
Excuse me.
Why do the kids have to be here?
Can you let them go?
Please?
You'll all be getting off soon. Okay?
Why are you doing this, man?
You don't need to know.
Now take a seat.
Why don't you tell me what's going on
and then I'll take a seat.
Like I said, this will be over soon.
Hey, stop!
Help!
Fuck!
It's over.
I hold my head up
Just enough to see the sky
And when we go
We won't go slow
We'll put up such a fight
And you will be one day
Exactly what you are
Just keep your head held high
Kiss your fist and touch the sky
Too late to keep the world from dying
One day
Whoo
We'll all be there
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Thanks for swinging this, Zahra.
I know it can't have been easy.
Yeah, they pulled him out
of the lunch queue at Belmarsh,
so no doubt he'll be in a charming mood.
Come on.
I'll just be on the other side
of the glass.
If he sees me, he'll lose his shit.
Okay.
Turn.
Who the fuck are you?
Search him.
You won't find anything, okay?
I'm not armed. I don't have a gun.
I knew it.
What's he got?
Just a portable radio and keys.
No, no.
Stop the train.
- Don't listen to them, Otto.
- Wait. Wait.
Otto, don't listen to them.
- Jesus.
- Shut up.
Stop the train.
Otto!
No, no. We have…
- We have to keep going.
- No, no. It's okay. He's unarmed.
The hijack's over.
We're all gonna get off,
so you better stop the fucking train.
Please.
- Let's get out of here.
- You don't wanna do that.
Shut up! I've had enough of your bullshit.
I'll get the others.
No, no. If anyone steps off this train,
you all die.
The explosives will detonate
if anybody gets off.
He's right.
- Where are these fucking bombs?
- Under the train.
If you don't believe me, just look.
All right. Otto, Otto. Show 'em.
Hey, hey, hey.
One hundred kilos of sodium chlorate
and sugar primed with Semtex.
Forensics analyzed everything
from the bomb maker's apartment,
as well as the residue I found.
You should have the full report now.
Oh, my God.
And the triggers for these bombs,
can you stop them remotely?
No. The system is air-gapped.
If you get me under the train,
I might have a chance, but otherwise…
Okay, but how does someone like Sam
even meet a bomb maker like this?
Good question, Miss Thatcher.
Allow me…
You a cop or something?
BKA.
Is this your place?
My German runs to, "The Pilsner is off"
and, "No, we don't give credit."
You'd remember him, right?
If he'd been in here?
I'm not good with faces.
So you're a regular, yes?
Ever seen him in here?
Yesterday, I think.
What time?
Around 7.
He was sat over there…
…with another British guy.
British?
Yeah.
Kind of an officer type.
A bit… full of himself.
Where are you taking me?
Anyone?
You two idiots
are supposed to be protecting me,
and here we are driving around
in broad daylight.
Three months of this shit.
I hope this madman
ties you to the tracks.
Seriously, Lang,
where the hell are we going, eh?
Control…
We're 27 minutes out from Bergmannstrasse.
Deactivate them.
- Now.
- I can't.
No, you must have a detonator,
a trigger or something.
I don't. I don't even know
how many there are.
What do you mean you don't know?
What's going on?
Where are you off to?
I've had enough of your bullshit!
You're not hearing me, okay?
I'm not in control here.
What are you talking about?
I'm being forced to do this.
- By who?
- I don't know who.
You know what?
It doesn't matter who it is.
One thing I do know is that if things
do not go the way they want it to go,
they will blow this train up.
Maybe one, two or three of you
might get off, but the rest…
But if you listen to me…
I can get you out of this.
Still nothing from the train?
No, not since they stopped.
I don't like it.
You need to speak to Nelson.
You heard him.
No contact until Bergmannstrasse.
How do you even know he'll be there?
We have an agreement.
Hello?
If you can't guarantee
he'll be at the handover,
then you must stop the convoy.
I'm not really
supposed to be talking to you.
Why would I do that?
Hear me out. This is what we need to do.
They need to believe
that I'm still the hijacker.
- You are.
- I'm not.
They made me hijack this train,
and they told me that someone will…
would be watching me the whole time.
Who? Who's watching you?
- Was it whoever killed Freddie?
- He killed Freddie.
- What if there is someone else?
- What about him?
Yeah, you.
He's obviously in on this.
I didn't hurt anyone.
Well, then who did?
You must know something.
It all happened down there, didn't it?
- Hey. Listen, he's just a driver, okay?
- I'm talking to you!
Neither of us wanted anyone to die.
Eight bombs.
Two under each carriage.
Jesus.
You don't want anyone to get hurt?
You got a funny way of showing it.
Sam, this is Polizeipräsidentin Winter.
I know you didn't want to hear from us,
but we can see you have stopped.
Is everything all right?
Sam, I need you to confirm
that everyone is okay,
so we can proceed with the handover
at Bergmannstrasse.
Hold on. Handover? What handover?
What's she talking about?
Answer me!
Okay. There is a man, all right?
He's a high-profile criminal.
He's being held here in Berlin.
And the people behind this,
the people that forced me to do this
wanted me to hijack this train,
and exchange all of you for him.
Right. So we're collateral?
Yes.
The police won't do the exchange
unless there are lives at risk.
Is that supposed to make us feel better?
Sam, speak to me.
Yes.
All right?
'Cause she will not hand him over
until you get off this train first.
So, you want us to carry on
being hostages?
That is the best chance
of you staying alive.
Look.
This is Wagon 2600.
We are about 20 minutes
from Bergmannstrasse.
Otto! Are you okay?
Where is Sam?
I'm here. Everything's on schedule.
When we pull into Bergmannstrasse,
if John Bailey-Brown is there,
then all these passengers
will get off the train.
Sam, that's very good to hear.
I'm glad we're communicating again.
Listen, if you stop messing me about
and start helping,
there are things that I can do.
I'm behind bars, Detective.
I know about as much as you do, which is
becoming very apparent, is sweet FA.
OCG have got their fingerprints
all over this.
I just wanna know what you've heard.
I haven't heard anything about
what's going on in Berlin.
So you agree something is going on?
Come on, Stuart,
I know you're not an idiot.
You're on remand, yeah?
I could speak to the CPS,
see if I can't make your situation
a little bit more comfortable.
A few more privileges, bigger cell.
And who knows, maybe we could even
shave a few years off.
You can offer me the moon on a fucking
stick for all the good it'll do you.
She'll tell you that.
Amazing to me.
This is what you lot do, innit?
Always looking out for your own bollocks.
And look where that got you.
…have released very little
as an official statement,
but we now understand that
the perpetrator is a British national.
The Bundespolizei, who are controlling
the emergency response,
have refused to identify this person…
- Welcome.
- …or comment on any possible…
The glamorous life of a spy.
Lang and I have been working out of
this office for the past six months.
Perhaps the only two people on the planet
more obsessed with John Bailey-Brown
than Sam Nelson is.
May I?
So I'm just a courier?
I've said from the beginning,
Sam can't be behind all this.
I'm willing to bet that the proof
is somewhere in there.
Did you…
Did you tell Winter you were coming?
I'm not the one going around
behind people's backs.
There's a lot here.
Like I said, he was persistent.
He was also vulnerable.
A vengeful father fixated on the man
who he believes killed his son.
Sam Nelson is the perfect mark,
lured to Berlin
to do someone else's dirty work.
And the CCTV evidence was the final piece.
When we found out Bailey-Brown was here,
we told the Germans to destroy
any evidence, including the CCTV.
That's how we've kept the whole project
under the radar.
I oversaw it personally.
But clearly someone chose
to keep a little souvenir.
Who?
I've burned through all my contacts.
Do you know anyone
in Berlin who could help?
There is someone.
Good.
Set it up, and let's find out
who sent that to Nelson.
ETA 7 minutes.
Who is this guy?
The guy we're all being exchanged for.
I mean, he must be some big fucking cheese
to be worth hundreds of us.
I think you owe us an explanation.
Who is he?
You must know.
Surely he told you.
Why are you trying to free the man
that killed your son?
Because they have his mother.
And they will kill her too,
unless I do exactly as they say.
Now you know.
Yeah?
Okay, but that's just one person.
There's so many of us.
Leave it.
All right.
We'll come back and deal with this later.
For now it's out of sight.
What else could we do?
Keep her up here and keep her in the dark,
that's what they said.
Tomorrow she can tell the police
all she saw was rain, sheep,
and a pair of good-looking farmers.
You off already?
No, just out for a walk.
Looks like you scared off your stalker.
Yeah. Looks like it.
Well, have a good one.
Yeah.
How long was she there?
I don't know…
I thought she was back at the house.
Alasdair.
Fuck.
They want me to wrap this up.
What do you reckon?
It's up to you, mate.
I've got nowhere else to be.
That's right.
After this you'll go back to Belmarsh
for the rest of your days,
and whilst you're keeping shtum,
there's nothing either of us can do
to change that.
Yeah, well, that's the life.
Wasn't the life for Lewis though, was it?
Your little brother.
Or your dad.
The Cheapside Firm,
they just chewed him up, spat him out.
But that's what they do.
Wasn't the life for Elaine either.
I was there.
I was the last person to speak to her
before she was killed.
Mum wasn't killed.
She chose to die.
That what you're telling yourself?
That it was… it was honorable?
Your mum was on the run.
She was alone, and she was scared.
You talk to me, Stuart.
Help me out.
Before you end up like her.
Sam Nelson, the hero of flight KA29,
has hijacked an underground train.
There you go.
Got a TV in my cell.
The bit that's not on the news is why.
John Bailey-Brown.
That's who he's asking for.
And the Germans are just gonna
hand him over, are they?
Looks that way, yeah.
So you believe my old firm
have staged a hijacking
to bust Bailey-Brown out of jail.
Well, let's just say
they got a bit of previous.
And you think
I could shed some light on it?
You're not on the record.
This won't come back to you.
You talk to me, Stuart.
Look, you could help a lot of people.
That's why we're here.
It's not about helping me.
It's not about helping Sam Nelson.
This is about saving lives.
You think the Kingdom hijacking
went well for me?
I was put on that plane to die.
That was the plan.
And when that failed,
I took the fall for what happened.
Now, I either die in jail
or I die out there
like the rest of my family.
That's the life.
And I made peace with it.
I'm totally cut off.
I'm nothing.
I know nothing. I am nothing.
Is this really necessary?
There's no way she saw anything.
She's stuck there now.
There's no phone signal.
And even if she does know,
what is she gonna do?
The point is we need to make sure.
Come on.
- What are you gonna do?
- Give me the knife.
Quick.
- Knife.
- Here you are.
- Give me your hand.
- What?
I'm so, so, sorry about this, Miss,
but my uncle here,
he's only gone
and cut himself climbing a wall.
He still thinks he's 17.
Oh, God.
You wouldn't have anything
to clean it up, would you?
Yeah, of course. Come in.
- Thank you. Thanks.
- Aye.
I'm not buying it.
You don't believe him?
- He really did lose his son.
- Not that.
The fact that we're just supposed
to sit here and let it all happen.
It's our best chance of surviving.
He said he wasn't in control.
He said they are watching him.
Yes.
They must be on this train.
The person who killed Freddie?
Exactly.
The real murderer is among us,
and we are supposed to ignore that?
Look what happened the last time
I listened to your theories.
You're on your own.
- Sorry, love. Did I wake you?
- No, I wasn't sleeping.
Hey, baby. Hey.
Don't worry. Daddy will be home soon.
Leah?
How long until we reach the station?
Five minutes.
Do you hear that? Just a few more minutes.
Could I borrow your phone?
Me? My phone? No, I don't have a phone.
What about yours?
We threw 'em all out.
Did we?
Can I borrow yours?
I don't have mine either.
It's okay.
I understand
why you would keep it a secret.
I don't have a phone
in my bag, lady. Jesus.
- Hey!
- Hey, stop!
Take it easy!
- Guys, guys, guys. Take it easy.
- Hey! Fuck.
- I've seen this before.
- Don't touch that.
It controls the bombs.
It's her! She's the one!
He's right.
That's what that does. All right?
You said you didn't know
who was controlling the bombs.
- What else have you been lying about?
- Shit. Stop the train.
No, no. Otto!
- Stop the train!
- No! No!
He's doing it again.
It says it's armed. How do we stop it?
- By giving it back to me.
- No chance.
- Sam.
- You were doing so well.
Sam.
We have to stop the convoy.
Try him one last time.
Sam?
Abort.
Copy that.
Get us off the street.
What's happening?
Apparently
there's some issue with the train.
There's no time for this.
We were just about to
pull into Bergmannstrasse.
You were getting exactly what you want.
So just stop this now.
- I will if they give it back to me.
- No, we're not giving you the detonator.
It's a timer, okay?
I need to reset it every 15 minutes.
A code for each carriage.
If I don't, the bombs will detonate!
Well, what's the code? I'll do it.
No. Give it to me, or you all die!
That means you die too.
It's not worth it.
Just give us the code.
Eight, three, four, nine.
Four, six, one, two.
One, five, three, four.
Eight, seven, five, three.
What did you do? What does that mean?
It means we're too late.
- So that's it?
- How do we stop it?
The explosives just detonate?
It's the rear carriage.
Untie me. Come on.
Come on, Mei.
- How long do we have?
- I don't know.
What? Where are those keys?
- Otto!
- The door. They're in the door.
I need to get everyone away
from the back of the train.
- Get on the radio and tell them to move.
- Okay.
Move! Move!
Everyone, go to the front
of the train now!
What's happening?
I should have kept my mouth shut.
Darling!
Go! Everyone go!
Come on! Come on! Quicker!
Go! First carriage.
What are you doing? Come on!
Now! Everyone! Go!
What are you waiting for? Let's move!
Get out the carriage, now! Let's go!
Come on! Get out of the carriage.
Let's go!
Go, go, go! Go! Come on!
It's about to blow.
Get all the way to the front!
Go on. Come on, let's go! Go, go, go!
Petra!
- Why? What's going on?
- Just go, now! Come on!
Let's go, let's go!
Clear the carriage--
We played this game
So many times before
In and out of my life
Like a revolving door
I'm still a man
Can't take it no more
Ooh ooh ooh hoo
Lord have mercy
I'm still a man